

# Alex Shepel

Kropyvnytskyi, Ukraine. Ready to relocate.



+38 (099) 220-7726 Please mail in advance.



linkedin.com/in/alexshepel



github.com/alex-shepel



iam.alex.shepel@gmail.com



t.me/AlexShepel



#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a man who loves challenges. I have worked in various positions. I started my career as an electrical engineer. Then I completed Stanford's CS106 course and started coding with simple scripts for computation automatizations and the programming of digital devices. I was creating web interfaces for the embedded systems. Eventually, I fully switched to web development. I was implementing corporative sites and healthcare applications. This includes authorizations with Google and Apple services, complex forms, tables, difficult adaptive components, working with the databases, and creating migrations, services, and controllers.

#### **LAST PROJECTS**

## Web app for Canada/UK clinics management

App administrates doctors and patients activity in different clinics.

#### Hardest tasks:

- construct large tables from correspondent JSON files descriptions (rows/cols schema, filters, nested components, different cells elements displaying logic).
- construct large forms with difficult dependencies between the fields
- write a lot of forms validation
- implement and optimize client side parsing, filtering and sorting of large data sets
- handle large redux store with many slices
- implement extendable reusable components
- implement adaptive pages that contain many different components

### Corporate website for internal use

App helps to collaborate with colleges, makes HR's and PM's job easier.

#### Tacke

- construct vacation and quizzes forms
- implement adaptive components
- write markup

#### Frontend for embedded device server

Device plugs-in the laptop and runs local server. Laptop downloads web app from device and runs browser. App implements interface for configuration and monitoring of device work.

#### Tasks

- implement real time displaying of the harmonics and vector diagrams on canvas
- compute missing parameters on the client side
- write markup

#### **SKILLS**

- React, hooks, router, redux, thunk, formik, react-query
- Node, express, nest, rest api, postgresql, sendgrid, jsonwebtoken, migrations
- Js es6+, ts, ajax, axios, lodash
- Html, css, sass/less, responsive/adaptive design, bootstrap, materialui
- Git, gitflow
- Webpack, parcel
- Maths and CS background

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Intermediate EN
- Native UA

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Frontend Developer**

Abto Software, Ukraine

FEBRUARY 2021 - PRESENT (1 year)

I am implementing healthcare applications.

## **Fullstack Developer**

ITLabel, Ukraine

AUGUST 2021 - PRESENT (2 years)

I am implementing corporative sites. This includes authorizations with Google and Apple services, complex forms, tables, difficult adaptive components, working with the databases, and creating migrations, services, and controllers.

## Design and development engineer

RPC Radiy, Ukraine

JANUARY 2020 - AUGUST 2021 (1.5 year)

I designed a digital power system protection. I built models in the Matlab Simulink and prototyped them on Intel FPGA. I was writing Java, JS, Python scripts for computations automatization.

## Maths and physics tutor

Freelance, Ukraine

AUGUST 2019 - APRIL 2020 (0.5 year)

I worked as a tutor for pupils and students.

## Engineer of relay/digital power system protection

PrJSC Kirovohrad Oblenergo, Ukraine

OCTOBER 2018 - JANUARY 2020 (1.5 year)

That is my master's specialization. I maintained an electrical power system protection and programmed new digital devices.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **MERN Fullstack Dev**

Programming school GoIT, Ukraine

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT (0.5 year)

## Stanford CS106 P2P program

Programming school III++, Ukraine

JUNE 2020 - JUNE 2021 (1 year)

## Master Degree in Electrical Engineering

Central Ukrainian National Technical University

SEPTEMBER 2014 - AUGUST 2020 (5 years)